Guide to the E. Clowes Chorley Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Autograph Collection, Series I
  - Autograph letters
    - Rand, Stuart C., 1937 October 16 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Randall, George Maxwell, 1810-1873, 1868 February 6 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Randolph, Alfred Magill, 1836-1918, 1899 October 6 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Randolph, Anson D. F., 1854 April 1 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Reese, Frederick Focke, 1854-, 1919 May 24 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Reese, Theodore Irving, 1873-1931, 1918 September 14 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Remington, William Proctor, 1879-, 1919 September 15 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Restarick, Henry Bond, 1854-1933, 1902 September 19, 1815 April 28 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Rhinelander, Philip Mercer, 1869-, 1924 February 15, September 30 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Rice, Maxwell, 1932 December 10 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Riley, Henry Chauncey, 1835-, 1876 February 3, 1885 March 30 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Robbins, Howard Chandler, 1876-, 1932 June 7, 1934 October 1 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Roberts, William Blair, 1881-, 1923 January 18 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Robertson, Charles Franklin, 1835-1886, 1881 December 10, 1883 October 14 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Robinson, Henry Douglas, 1859-1913, 1909 September 1 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Roots, Logan Herbert, 1870, 1916 October 27 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Rowe, Peter Trimble, 1856-, 1924 April 25. 1925 December 14 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Rulison, Nelson Somerville, 1842-1897, 1894 January 20 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Rutter, William Ives, Jr., 1924 February 6, 1931 January 27 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Sage, John Charles, 1866-1919, 1918 July 5 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Sanford, Louis Childs, 1867-, 1924 April 4, 1945 April 4 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Satterlee, Henry Yates, 1843-1908, 1897 November 11, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Scadding, Charles, 1861-1914, 1911 January 30 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Scarboroughm John, 1831-1914, 1885 March 9, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Schereschewsky, Samuel Isaac Joseph, 1831-1906, 1890 October 14 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Scott, Thomas Fielding, 1807-1867, 1861 February 27 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Sessums, Davis, 1858-1929, 1915 April 19 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Seymour, George Franklin, 1829-1906, 1883 September 28, 1886 July 9, 1887 March 25 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Shayler, Ernest Vincent, 1868-, 1919 June 9 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Sherrill, Henry Knox, 1890-, [1930] October 9 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Sherwood, Granville Hudson, 1878-1923, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Shipman, Herbert, 1869-1930, 1922 January 6, 1924 October 20, 1927 September 12 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Skinner, John, bp. of Aberdeen, 1744-1816, 1788 February 21 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Slattery, Charles Lewis, 1867-1930, 1921 March 30, May 9, 1922 August 5, 1923 March 24, 1924 May 15 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Smith, Benjamin Bosworth, 1794-1884, 1879 March 9, 1881 June 10 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Smith, Edmund Banks, 1914 July 23 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Smythe, George Franklin, 1924 May 16 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Southgate, Horatio, 1812-1894, 1891 February 18 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Spalding, Franklin Spencer, 1865-1914, 1907 November 13 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Spalding, John Franklin, 1828-1902, 1873 December 10, 1888 November 3 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Sprague, William Buell, 1795-1876, 1855 January 31 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Starkey, Thomas Alfred, 1818-1903, 1899 October 3 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Stearly, Wilson Reiff, 1869-, 1921 April 26 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Sterrelt, Frank William, 1885-, 1924 January 12 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Stevens, William Bertrand, 1884-, 1939 November 3, December 6, 1944 April 3, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Stires, Ernest Milmore, 1866-, 1925 June 17, July 15 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Stoney, James M., 1944 February 2 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Sumner, Walter Taylor, 1922 May 1 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Talbot, Etherbert, 1848-1928, 1921 April 2 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Temple, Edward Arthur, 1867-1924, 1915 April 15 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Temple, William, abp. of Canterbury, 1881-, 1916 November 24 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Thomas, Albert Sidney, 1873-, 1944 March 22, November 19 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Thomas, Elisha Smith, 1834-1895, 1892 October 12 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Thomas, Nathaniel Seymour, 1867, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Thomas, William Matthews Merrick, 1878-, 1928 October 3 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Thompson, Hugh Miller, 1830-1902, 1896 October 10 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Thompson, Arthur Conover, 1871-, [1921 Apr?] (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Thurston, Theodore Payne, 1867-, 1924 January 21 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Touret, Frank Hale, 1875-, 1918 April 19 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Tucker, Beverley Dandridge, 1846-1930, [1919?] September 15 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Tucker, H. St. George, 1926 January 31 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Turner, Samuel Hulbeart, 1790-1861, 1819 September 13, 1858 October 21 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Tuttle, Daniel Sylvester, 1837-1923, 1916 June 30, July 12, August 10, September 2 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Tyler, John Poyntz, 1862-1931, 1915 April 22, 1919 March 29 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Tyng, Stephen Higginson, 1862 November 10 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Upfold, George, 1796-1872, 1848 July 21, 1863 May 22 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Vail, Thomas Hubbard, 1812-1889, 1887 March 11 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Van Buren, James Heartt, 1850-1917, 1915 April 29 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Van Dyck, Vedder, 1889-, 1935 November 25, 1941 September 29 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Van Ingen, Jn. V., 1837 October 16 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Vincent, Boyd, 1845-1935, 1921 April 27 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Vinton, Francis, 1809-1872, 1852 January 30 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Wainwright, Jonathan Mayhew, 1792-1854, 1854 June 19 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Ward, John Chamberlain, 1873-, 1922 June 2 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Webb, William Walter, 1857-1933, 1922 July 17 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Weller, Reginals Heber, 1857-, 1917 September 13 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Welles, Edward Randolph, 1830-1888, 1884 January 16 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Wells, Lemuel Henry, 1841-1936, 1899 August 15 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Whipple, Henry Benjamin, 1822-1901, 1862 December 22, 1886 July 10, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Whitaker, Ozi William, 1830-1911, 1889 November 29 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - White, John Chanler, 1867-, 1924 March 12, 1944 March 8 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - White, John Hazen, 1849-1925, 1899 July 22 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Whitehead, Cortlandt, 1842-1922, 1899 October 5 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Whitehouse, Henry John, 1803-1874, 1874 June 17 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Whittingham, William Rollinson, 1805-1879, 1841 January 27, December 18, 1843 March 2, 1868 December 22 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Williams, Charles David, 1860-1923, 1917 August 13 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Williams, Gershom Mott, 1857-1923, 1916 February 3 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Williams, Granville Mercer, 1937 March 9 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Williams, John, 1817-1899, 1875 March 18, 1882 August 19, 1883 September 27, 1884 July 2, 1891 March 17 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Wilmer, Joseph Pere Bell, 1812-1878, [1868] December 24, 1869 January 18 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Wilmer, Richard Hooker, 1816-1900, 1868 December 28, 1886 July 30 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Wilson, R_____ H., 1919 March 27 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Winchester, James Ridout, 1852-, 1915 April 14 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Wingfield, John Henry Ducachet, 1833-1898, 1894 August 7 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Winton, Theodore, 1929 November 1 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Wise, James, 1875-, 1924 September 25, 1933 January 3 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Woodcock, Charles Edward, 1854-, 1919 September 11 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Worthington, George, 1840-1908, 1881 October 3, 1883 September 28, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Young, John Freeman, 1820-1885, 1868 December 30 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Unidentified, 1905, 1921, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous autographs, 1882, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Research Papers, Series II
  - Papers relating to the Protestant Episcopal Church in Mexico
    - Letters and documents, 1875-1884 (Box 2, Folder 39-43)
      See also: box 4, folder 82
    - [Lee, Alfred?]: "Report to the Mexican Commission", undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Notes and printed matter, 1898-1915, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Sermons
    - Bass, Edward (1726-1803): "Gen. 2d. 17th", 1765 April 19 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Bratton, Theodore DuBose (1862-): sermon at the opening of the 48th general convention (typescript), 1925 October 7 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Brent, Charles Henry (1862-): sermon at the consecration of Bishop Stires (typescript), 1925 February 24 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Burgess, Frederick (1853-1925): "5 Revelation XXI", undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - [Elliott, Stephen (-1866)?]: "St. Matthew. Ch. 22:29", 1859 April 24 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Furse, Michael Bolton (1870-): sermon at the opening of the 50th general convention (typescript), 1931. September 16 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Howe, ______: funeral sermon for Bishop Alfred Lee, 1887 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Lee, Alfred (1807-1887)
      - "Christ glorified in his saints", 1840 February 9 (Box 3, Folder 53)
      - "The seal of the spirit", 1840 [June 7] (Box 3, Folder 54)
      - "Occasion of the President's death", 1841 May 14 (Box 3, Folder 55)
      - "Excellency of the Knowledge of Christ", 1843 May (Box 3, Folder 56)
      - "The Life and Ministry of Benjamin Boseworth Smith", 1884 September 24 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Manning, William Thomas (1866-): sermon at the consecration of Bishop Gilbert, 1930 October 28 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Moore, Benjamin: "II Tim. iv. 5" (printed), 1787 July 15 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Provoost, Samuel: "Acts 20-35", 1787 November (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Books, articles, addresses, etc.
    - Allen, Ethan: "American Ecclesiastical History. Maryland Toleration", undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Beardsley, E. Edwards: "The Rev. Jeremiah Leaming, D.D.," The Churchman, 1885 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Cheshire, Joseph Blount (1850-1932): "The Fundamental Constitutions of Carolina, and Religious Liberty in the Province of North Carolina,", [1915 Dec?] (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Brown, William M. (1855-1937): 2 pages of his defense against a charge of heresy, 1925 October (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Coxe, Arthur Cleveland (1818-1896): poem, "The Day of Palms", [1889?) (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Hart, Samuel
      - "Bi-centenary of the Church in Connecticut" (printed), [1907?] (Box 3, Folder 66)
      - "How Our Church Came to Connecticut," The Young Churchman, undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Mackenzie, Kenneth: "A Brief History of the Church of the Holy Trinity in the City of New York" (illustrated with photographs), 1915 June (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Mampoteng, Charles: "Benjamin Moore, Bishop of New York and President of Columbia College," Columbia University Quarterly, pp. 165-189, 1936 September (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Mansfield, Burton: "Foundation of the Church in Connecticut," The Spirit of Missions, pp. 353-356, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - [Midwinter, Sir Edward Colpoys (1872-)?]: "The S.P.G. in America," at the 150th anniversary of the 1st general convention, [1935 September 27?] (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Moore, Benjamin: "A Charge Delivered to the Convention of the Protestant Episcopal Church in the State of New York" (printed), 1808 October 5 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Potter, Henry Codman (1835-1909): lecture on Mormonism, [1871?] (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Riley, Athelstan (1858-): hymn written for E.C. Chorley, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Seymour, George Dudley: The Reverend Jeremiah Leaming, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Spencer, Jesse Ames (1816-1898): "Young People's Library of Church History. Vol. 4. History of the Reformation in England", 1881 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Anonymous
      - "Tour to New York via Hartford & New Haven May 1829. Tour to Phila. Genl. Convention Augt. 1829", 1829 May, August (Box 4, Folder 77)
      - "On hearing the disgraceful result of Bishop Benjamin T. Onderdonk's Trial", [1845] January 8 (Box 4, Folder 78)
      - "Early Church in Connecticut," American Ecclesiastical History, pp. 106-120, 1857 April (Box 4, Folder 79)
      - The Services of the Protestant Episcopal Church in the United States of America, as ordered by The Bishops During the Civil War, 1864 February 22 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Documents, minutes, etc.
    General note
    Folio
    - New York City. Protestant Episcopal Sunday School Society: printed constitution, with manuscript resolution, 1835 April 15 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Diocese of Western New York. Standing Committee: resolutions and minutes, 1838 November 2 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - "An Appeal to the Church in behalf of the Greek Mission" (facsimile), [1860 August 25] (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - General Convention of the Protestant Episcopal Church. House of Deputies: resolutions, 1874 October 13 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Church of the Holy Trinity (New York City): minutes of meetings of the committee appointed to raise funds for the American Church in Florence, Italy, with list of rectors compiled by Samuel Coffey, 1920 Nov 30, 1880-1887 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Scrapbook of the general convention of the Protestant Episcopal Church, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1949, undated (Box 4, Folder 86)
- Writings of E.C. Chorley, Series III
  - Articles and addresses
    - "Chapter. Nevada" (typescript), [1922] (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - "The General Convention," [written for The Churchman ?] (typescript), [1925] October 6-9 (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - "Historical Address at the Re-opening of St. Peter's Church, Cortlandville, N.Y." (typescript), 1926 July 5 (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Jarvis papers
      - "Letters of Reverend Doctor Ebenezer Dibblee, of Stamford," Vol. 1, Historical Magazine of the Protestant Episcopal Church, pp. 51-89 (typescript), 1932 June (Box 5, Folder 90)
      - "Letters of the Rev. Dr. Leaming to the Rev. Dr. Samuel Peters," Historical Magazine of the Protestant Episcopal Church, Vol. 1, pp. 116-142, 179-203 (typescript), 1932 Sep, December (Box 5, Folder 91)
      - "Letters from the Reverend Dr. Miles Cooper," Historical Magazine of the Protestant Episcopal Church, Vol. 2, No. 1, pp. 44-47 (typescript), 1933 March (Box 5, Folder 92)
      - "Samuel Provoost - First Bishop of New York," Historical Magazine of the Protestant Episcopal Church, Vol. 2, No. 2, pp. 1-25; No. 3, pp. 1-16 (typescript), 1933 Jun, September (Box 5, Folder 93)
      - "Conventions of the Clergy of Connecticut" (typescript), [ca. 1932-1933] (Box 5, Folder 94)
      - "The Letters of the Reverend Samuel Seabury, D.D." (typescript), [ca. 1932-1933] (Box 5, Folder 95-96)
      - "A Paper on the Church in Connecticut" (typescript), [ca. 1932-1933] (Box 5, Folder 97)
      - "Papers Relating to Revision of the English Book of Common Prayer" (typescript), [ca. 1932-1933] (Box 5, Folder 98)
      - Miscellaneous, [ca. 1932-1933] (Box 5, Folder 99)
        See also: Oversize
    - "Early Days at Saint Clement's, Philadelphia" (typescript), [1932] (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - "Benjamin Moore, Second Bishop" (typescript), undated (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - "Benjamin Tredwell Onderdonk, Fourth Bishop" (typescript), undated (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - "Chapter I. The Robinson Family in England and Virginia" (manuscript) (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - "Henry B. Whipple - the Apostle of the Indians" (manuscript), undated (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - "Interview with Bishop Greer" (typescript), undated (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - Notes
    - "American Church Missionary Society", undated (Box 6, Folder 106)
    - "The Church in Africa", undated (Box 6, Folder 107)
    - "The Church in Virginia", undated (Box 6, Folder 108)
    - "Colonial Church", undated (Box 6, Folder 109)
    - "Colored Work", undated (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - "Idaho", undated (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - "Iowa", undated (Box 6, Folder 112)
    - "Long Island", undated (Box 6, Folder 113)
    - "Medical Missions", undated (Box 6, Folder 114)
    - "Montana", undated (Box 6, Folder 115)
    - "Nevada", undated (Box 6, Folder 116)
    - Miscellaneous, 1941 January 30 (Box 6, Folder 117)
  - Bibliographies and inventories
    - "Dioceses. Alabama to New Jersey", undated (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - "Dioceses. New York City & State", undated (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - "Dioceses. N. Car….Wyoming", undated (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - "Presentment, Trial, and Sentence of Bishop Benjamin T. Onderdonk….Bishop Geo. Washington Doane….Bishop William M. Brown", undated (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - "Protestant Episcopal Church", undated (Box 6, Folder 122)
    - Inventory of documents, printed matter, etc. relating to the Protestant Episcopal Church, undated (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - Lists of Protestant Episcopal bishop autographs, undated (Box 6, Folder 124)
  - Diary, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 125)
- Oversize
  - Papers relating to the Protestant Episcopal Church in Mexico: synod ratification of the covenant, 1875 August (Box 7)
  - "An Appeal to the Church in behalf of the Greek Mission" (facsimile), [1860 August 25] (Box 7)
  - Jarvis papers: application for bishopric (facsimile), 1784 November 15 (Box 7)